This privacy policy sets out how _fruux_ uses and protects any information that you provide us when you use our website and/or our software/services.

We are committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. When we collect data during your visit either to this website and/or through the use of our software/services by which you can be identified, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement and the appropriate data protection laws. Any data collected will not be publicly disclosed by us nor transferred to any third parties without your prior consent.

_fruux_ may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes. This policy is effective from January 1, 2008.

Recording and processing of data
--------------------------------

When you visit this website and/or use our software/services, our servers make a temporary record of each access and stores it in a log file. The following data is recorded and stored until it is automatically deleted:

* IP address of the requesting device
* Date and time of access
* Name and URL of the file downloaded
* Amount of data transmitted
* An indication whether the download was successful
* Data identifying the browser and operating system
* The website from which our site was accessed
* Name of your ISP (internet service provider)

Additionally we use Google Analytics in order to track the usage of our website.

The purpose of recording this data is to:

* allow use of the website (connection setup)
* maintain overall system security
* allow technical administration of our network infrastructure
* optimise our internet services.

We do not compile personal profiles of any of our users. The German Telemedia Act (TMG - _Telemediengesetz_) states that user profiles are permissible under the condition that pseudonyms are used and on condition that the user does not withhold consent. If we do intend to use this condition anywhere on our website, a notice informing you of your right to withdraw consent will be posted on the respective page(s).

Apart from the exceptions stated above, we do not process any personal data without first obtaining your expressed consent to do so.

Use and transfer of personal data
---------------------------------

Any usage of your personal data is confined to the purposes as stated above and will only be undertaken to the extent necessary for these purposes.

Any personal data will not be transferred to government bodies or public authorities with the exception of compliance with mandatory national legislation or if the transfer of such data is necessary in order to take any legal action in case of fraudulent access to our network infrastructure. Personal data will not be transferred to third parties for any other purpose.

By using our software/services, you give _fruux_ the permissions that are needed to provide you with the software/services and the permissions that are necessary to provide you with certain features when you use them (for example, when you choose to create a public calendar). This permission also extends to trusted third parties that _fruux_ works with in order to provide you with the software/services, for example Amazon Web software/servicess (AWS), which provides our technical infrastructure. This permission also includes our design and programming standards that administer our software/services (for example how backup your data to avoid data loss).

Consent to use data in other contexts
-------------------------------------

Certain uses, such as using our software/services and our blog, our newsletters and/or discussion forums, require prior registration using an email address and requires more substancial usage of personal data, such as long-term storage of email addresses, user IDs and passwords. This data will only be used by _fruux_ insofar as you have provided us with such data and you have given us prior consent to use it. This data is only used in order to provide the respective service to you. We do not transfer your personal data to any third parties.

Security
--------

We are committed to ensuring that your personal information is secure. In order to prevent against inadvertent or deliberate manipulation, loss or destruction and unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable technical and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure any personal information that we collect online. Our security measures are constantly updated and improved in line with technological progress.

Cookies
-------

In particular exceptions we may use cookies which places a small file containing control data for that particular session in your browser's memory. This data is automatically deleted at the very latest when you close your browser.

If, in an exceptional case, one of our applications needs to store personal data in a cookie (for example a user ID) then we will alert you to this fact.

It is, of course, possible to use our website without using cookies however please note that most browsers are programmed to accept cookies in their default configuration. You can prevent this by changing the appropriate setting in your browser's options. If you set your browser to refuse all cookies then this may restrict the use of certain functions on our website.

Links to external websites
--------------------------

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement, nor can we guarantee that they conform to current data protection legislation. You should therefore exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

Controlling your personal information
-------------------------------------

You may at any time make a request to inspect any data stored concerning your person, to amend or delete this data as well withdraw your consent for its further use. If you are a registered user of certain services provided by _fruux_ then we may offer you the possibility of viewing this data online and even amending and deleting the data by yourself. You may request details of any personal information which we hold by you or make a demand for amendment and/or deletion. If you would like a copy of the information held on you, or if you have any further questions concerning the use of your personal data held by us, then please contact:

**privacy (at) fruux (dot) com**

Should you communicate with us by email, please be aware of the fact that the content of unencrypted emails can be intercepted and read openly by either unintended or unauthorised parties. We therefore recommend for this very reason that confidential information is transmitted in encrypted form or sent by post in order to guarantee complete security.

Acceptance and modification of this privacy policy
--------------------------------------------------

By using our website and/or other services, you implicitly agree that your personal data will be used in accordance with the privacy policy stated above. As our servies evolve and new technologies come into use, it may become necessary for us to amend this privacy policy statement from time to time. We therefore recommend that you read the updated version of this policy regularly to ensure that you are informed of the latest changes.
